Guide to the Hulce family papers, 1773-1899.
Hulce family papers, 1773-1899.(448)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hulce family papers, 1773-1899.
448
Hulce family.
4.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, records, contracts, accounts, inventories, surveys, deeds, expository accounts, plans, sketches, and other records and material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, records, contracts, accounts, inventories, surveys, deeds, expository accounts, plans, and other records and material pertaining to the activities of the Hulce family in Deposit, Delaware County, New York. Subjects include their lumbering interests along the Delaware River, the making of potash, a general store business, land speculation and real estate in New York, Pennsylvania, and the west, saw-mills, labor matters, waterpower, and brick-kilning. Areas of their especial interest include education, religion, politics (with particular reference to "Black Republicanism" and the Democratic Party), and temperance. Also included are historical sketches by Martial Hulce describing the early settlement of Deposit and vicinity.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Martial R. Hulce was a sheriff, justice of the peace, businessman, editor, publisher, surveyor, and attorney. Sylvester D. Hulce was a justice of the peace, editor, and businessman.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, records, contracts, accounts, inventories, surveys, deeds, expository accounts, plans, and other records and material pertaining to the activities of the Hulce family in Deposit, Delaware County, New York. Subjects include their lumbering interests along the Delaware River, the making of potash, a general store business, land speculation and real estate in New York, Pennsylvania, and the west, saw-mills, labor matters, waterpower, and brick-kilning. Areas of their especial interest include education, religion, politics (with particular reference to "Black Republicanism" and the Democratic Party), and temperance. Also included are historical sketches by Martial Hulce describing the early settlement of Deposit and vicinity. Papers pertaining to Deposit include post master's reports, local church records, records of the Deposit Bridge Company, plans for plank roads, records of the Deposit Volunteer Temperance Association, papers relating to the establishment of a Negro Sunday School (1864), and papers pertaining to the Deposit National Bank, Deposit Seminary, the New York and Erie Railroad, and other railroad, business, and local activities.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hulce family.; Hulce, Martial R.; Hulce, Sylvester D.; Democratic Party (U.S.); Deposit Bridge Company (Deposit, N.Y.); Deposit National Bank (Deposit, N.Y.); Deposit Seminary (Deposit, N.Y.); Deposit Volunteer Temperance Association.; New York and Erie Railroad.
Subjects:
General stores--New York (State)--Deposit.; Lumber trade--New York (State)--Deposit.; Lumber trade--New York (State)--Delaware County.; Saw-mills--New York (State)--Deposit.; Potash--New York (State)--Deposit.; Labor--New York (State)--Deposit.; Temperance--New York (State)--Deposit.; Mills and mill-work--New York (State)--Deposit.; African American Sunday schools--New York (State)--Deposit.; Kilns--New York (State)--Deposit.; Plank roads--New York (State)--Deposit.; Water-power--New York (State)--Deposit.; Real property--New York (State); Real property--Pennsylvania.; Railroads--New York (State)--Delaware County.; Family--New York (State)--Deposit.; Manufactures--Deposit (N.Y.); Sheriffs.; Justices of the peace.; Publishers.; Editors.; Surveyors.; Lawyers.
Places:
Deposit (N.Y.)--Social life and customs; Deposit (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Deposit (N.Y.)--History, Local.; Delaware County (N.Y.)--History, Local.; Deposit (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; Deposit (N.Y.)--Economic conditions.; Deposit (N.Y.)--Commerce.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.; Contracts.; Inventories.; Surveys.; Deeds.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Consists of collections #448, #690, and #579.
CONTAINER LIST
- Collection #448
  - 1773-1838 (Box 1)
  - 1839-1842 (Box 2)
  - 1843-1847 (Box 3)
  - 1848-1852 (Box 4)
  - 1853-1864 (Box 5)
  - 1865-1899 (Box 6)
  - Undated (Box 7)
- Collection #579
  - 1815-1839 (Box 1)
  - 1840-1850 (Box 2)
  - 1850-1859 (Box 3)
  - 1859-1879 (Box 4)
  - 1880-1893 (Box 5)
  - Franklin Baptist Association (Box 5)
  - Dell's Electric Railway (Box 5)
  - Map, 1807 (Box 5)
  - Map of Delaware County, N.Y., 1839 (Box 5)
  - Undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - 1903 correspondence to Profs. H.H. Wing and Geo. N. Lauman re: pledges for portrait of Prof. I.P. Roberts (Box 1 (black box))
- Collection #690
  - Sketches 1-4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sketches 5-8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sketches 9-12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sketches 13-16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sketches 18-12 (17 missing) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sketches 22, 24-26 (23 missing) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sketches 27, 29-31 (28 missing) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sketches 32-35 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sketches 36, 37, 39, 40 (38 missing) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sketches 41-44 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sketches 45-48 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sketches 49-52 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sketches 53-56 (Box 1, Folder 13)